Hello friends, today in the result season we are going to
talk
about insurance companies. The results of all three HDFC Life, ICICI PDL and ICICI
LB have come.  Let's
talk in a little detail.  See, the insurance
company is giving decent returns overall.   It has
not been exceptional for the last few years.  There
is also some underperformance from the market.  But it is
said that going forward the scope
is huge.  So of course there is no bus
in the insurance company also.  So if we
talk about the result, it was a decent result.  There was nothing
particularly explosive about it.  If we
talk about HDFC Ltd, if you see, there is a
quarter on quarter revenue jump
and even year on year but you know there was no
jump in profitability.
You will see that in ICICI PNC also there was no profit
year on year. ICICI PNC had comparatively
good results. In comparison to this, you
can say that if we talk about HDFC Ltd or even LBRD,
if you
look at LBRD year on year, there is a
growth of 12%,
but the profitability is low.  The same
problem is that there is no consistency
in the insurance company and to a large extent a
lot depends on the premium.
Even the rules of IRDA change.
Because of that also they face issues to a great extent.
If we talk about overall year on year growth,
how much growth
they have given.  No, if you look here, you will
see how in the last 5 years,
ICICI LBR has given a return of 17% in 3 years.
ICIL has performed well.  But
if we talk about HDFC L and them, then you will
see that almost all of
you HDFC L has a 3 year return of 7%.
ICICI P has a return of 12%.
And I have performed a little this year.  I came up
from my bottom a little.  But there
is no such significant result.  The reason is that as I
said, Covid had come.  Then later the
premiums changed again.  Later they
say that there has been an impact on income tax and
as it was said in income tax that it has been removed from ATCC, that
means ATCC will not be applicable
in the new reasoning and secondly,
due to GST rationalization,
GST was removed from the premium, due to which these people have also been
hit because they cannot
take credit, so that issue of premium will
continue for two-three more quarters, one or two more quarters,
due to which there will be
some impact on their profitability and this thing will
remain for some time because see what used to happen earlier was that they used to
set off their other expenses against the GST collected.  If
GST is not collected now,
other expenses will automatically get converted into expenses.
Correct.  So the same thing
is going to happen now and because of this they are
not rationalizing right now.  But yes, if the
premium may increase in one or two quarters, then we
can tell them that
their NPA may appear a little better.  If
we talk about what seems to be happening here
and how can growth come?  So
you will see that growth will come.  If we look at the
current premium growth, HDFC L is
around 9%.  ICICI's is around 4%
and ICICI LBR's is almost 13%.
Look at general insurance and it is said that there is
a little more growth there
because there is a good growth in health insurance.
And even if you see, the
way the sales of automobiles and all that have happened from
October to December, in a
way there will be a boom in insurance,
so comparatively Lumbard
is stable there, if you see AP also, the
annualized premium is almost Rs 3900 crore,
equivalent to HDFC L
is almost Rs 2500 crore, and from here also
if you see the detail focus, then of course HDFC
LCI is more in Lumbard, sorry ICICI Prudential.
Whereas if we
talk about Lambard, it is retail plus corporate.
Now how do you feel about going forward?  See,
their growth will also remain moderate in future.
Again ULIP and all that happens, so
in life insurance there is some ups and down in the margins
but the margin of ULIP is also
gradually decreasing and the protection
mix is ​​increasing in life insurance,
so due to that also there can be a
slight increase in the premium, the combined ratio if
we talk about general insurance
like ICIL is around 104-105% and the
underwriting discipline that is there
in ICICI, we will have to be a little careful
because
if something goes wrong in health insurance there, then there will be
problem in claims because they were quite
elevated in Q3 of ICICI Lomb,
going forward the management has said that they can become stable to some extent.
So
if we talk about the solvency ratio, then
see, there is no problem of solvency ratio in all these.
If you watch HDFC Live,
ICI Pencil is comfortable.  Even
Prudential, sorry, Lumb is also quite
comfortable and what about them, they are banks too, so a
good amount of oil is earned from banks as well,
but what do you feel from here, how can it
grow, like average
premium equivalent, that matrix has to be always
seen, so I feel that HDFC L can
grow by 12 to 14%, VNB can also
grow by almost 13 to 15%, so
going forward, if the enterprise value
grows by 13 to 15%, which
can give you a decent return.  Similarly, here also
in ICICI Dashal it seems that
your enterprise value will grow by 15%.
If your growth is more than 15% then these companies
can give you stable revenue.  But
ICICI Piden's figures are comparatively good.
And it looks like VNB growth is OK
value of new business.  VNB i.e.
Value of New Business will grow by 15 to 18%,
if we look at the premium till now, it has
grown by 1315.  So
if you look at it this way, it seems that
ICICI Pall may be growing faster than HDFC
Life in future, whereas if we
talk about ICICI LBR, its ROE also
seems that going forward it will grow at 14-15% and
ROE will also
normalize gradually.  So if we talk about valuation, it
is fine right now.
All these companies are not so elevated.  But going forward,
growth is also stable.  So
you cannot expect any such destructive returns from here.
But if someone
wants consistent returns, decent returns, then they
can go for that, but whether it will give 15% plus returns, then that becomes a
bit doubtful
because if you look at the past, then
that problem was there, yes, perhaps
in general insurance, you will be able to see some growth in that way going forward
because what has happened now is that as
I said, there is
demand for insurance in automobiles, even
in health insurance and many
people are saying that
from personal insurance to corporates, they also buy a lot of
insurance, so in that way ICICI LB will
benefit whereas HDFC Life, ICICI Life even have
two penetrations, but as I
said, the impact of GST rationalization remained a
little for them for two-three quarters, so
due to that, a little muted growth can be
seen there.  But overall, as I
said, the growth is good.  There is decent growth.
So if you want to invest keeping an eye on it that way, then do it.
Again,
no recommendations here.  Just for a knowledge I am
sharing.  Well, by the way, if you
want better knowledge or
understanding for this, then you must join our Twitter
channel.  I will
definitely put its link in the comment box.  Ok?   If
you have any comments related to this, please
post them in the comment box.  And if
you want any stock to be taken next then
I will try to cover it.  So
let's do it up to here.  So thank you very much
for joining.  See you soon next.  Bye.
Investment in market securities is
subject to market risk.  Read all the
documents carefully before investing.